<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Alexandre Amice</title><link>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://alexandreamice.github.io/media/icon_hu15baccefadde2163b605cbb3f225a5aa_10270_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Certified Polyhedral Descriptions of Configuration Space</title><link>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/c-iris/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/c-iris/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="motivation">Motivation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>TODO&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="contribution">Contribution&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>TODO&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- Understanding the geometry of collision-free configuration space (C-free) in the presence of task-space obstacles is an essential ingredient for collision-free motion planning. While it is possible to check for collisions at a point using standard algorithms, to date no practical method exists for computing C-free *regions* with rigorous certificates due to the complexity of mapping task-space obstacles through the kinematics. In this work, we present the first to our knowledge rigorous method for approximately decomposing a rational parametrization of C-free into certified polyhedral regions. Our method, called C-IRIS (C-space Iterative Regional Inflation by Semidefinite programming), generates large, convex polytopes in a rational parameterization of the configuration space which are rigorously certified to be collision-free. Such regions have been shown to be useful for both optimization-based and randomized motion planning. Based on convex optimization, our method works in arbitrary dimensions, only makes assumptions about the convexity of the obstacles in the *task* space, and is fast enough to scale to realistic problems in manipulation. We demonstrate our algorithm's ability to fill a non-trivial amount of collision-free C-space in several 2-DOF examples where the C-space can be visualized, as well as the scalability of our algorithm on a 7-DOF KUKA iiwa, a 6-DOF UR3e and 12-DOF bimanual manipulators. An implementation of our algorithm is open-sourced in [Drake](https://github.com/RobotLocomotion/drake). -->
&lt;h1 id="results">Results&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="a-two-dimensional-example">A Two Dimensional Example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We consider a simple two degree of freedom robot where we can visualize both the task space on the left and the configuration space obstacle on the right. The green dot in the configuration space represents the current configuration. The red region corresponds to the configuration space obstacle, i.e. if the green dot wanders into the red region we have a collision. We animate a trajectory through our certified region and show the separating plane certificates for the tips of the two robots. The animation can be replayed by opening the control menu and hitting play on the animation (you may need to minimize the scene tab).&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe
width="100%"
height="500"
src="pinball_trajectory.html"
frameborder="1"
allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"
allowfullscreen>
name="pinball_trajectory"
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;center>&lt;a href="pinball_trajectory.html" target="pinball_trajectory">View this animation in full screen&lt;/a>&lt;/center>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also provide a visualization of our algorithm growing regions in this configuration space below.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe
src="pinball_growth.html"
width="100%"
height="500"
frameborder="1"
allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"
allowfullscreen>
name="pinball_trajectory"
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;center>&lt;a href="pinball_growth.html" target="pinball_growth">View this animation in full screen&lt;/a>&lt;/center>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interactive code demonstration of this example is available via &lt;a href="https://deepnote.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deepnote&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="a-realistic-robot">A Realistic Robot&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our work scales to various realistic robots. In this example, a collision-free configuration space region is grown near a pre-grasp pose for a UR3e to grip the red object. The animation shows the range of configurations which are certified as collision-free near the object.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe
src="ur_single.html"
width="100%"
height="500"
frameborder="1"
allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"
allowfullscreen>
name="pinball_trajectory"
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;center>&lt;a href="ur_single.html" target="ur_single">View this animation in full screen&lt;/a>&lt;/center>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Structured Optimization</title><link>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/poset_least_squares/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/poset_least_squares/</guid><description>&lt;p>WORK IN PROGRESS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resilient Behavior Through Optimization</title><link>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/constraint_relax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/constraint_relax/</guid><description>&lt;p>WORK IN PROGRESS&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scheduling with Constraints</title><link>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/matroid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alexandreamice.github.io/project/matroid/</guid><description>&lt;p>WORK IN PROGRESS&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>